



MANOHAR PALANISAMY

Nationality: Indian (+91) 9819876078

Date of birth: 15/03/1995

Gender: Male

■ Email address: send2manoo@gmail.com

Website: http://bit.ly/MLNotesStanford

Website: http://bit.ly/ManoharPalanisamy

in LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/ManoharPalanisamyLinkedIn

Q Github: : http://bit.ly/GithubManohar

• Address: 229/2, Itteri Road, Varalakshmi Hall Back Meyyanur, Alagapuram, 636004

Salem (India)

ABOUT ME

I'm learned from failure, self-taught, independent, motivated and passionate about technology. I gathered knowledge from basic to advanced in Big Data, Parallel Computing, Machine learning, Neural Networks and Computer Vision. It is easy to grasp a term in Artificial Intelligence. I did plenty of projects in real-time. It made me proud being a researcher; I like two words from English, Discipline and Confidence. This is what I always believe to reach the goal. A guy who comes from nothing doesn't know computer, Now to deploy a deep learning model as the docker container into the AWS server and successfully classifies an object in real-time. I understand every bit and byte of a computer. Like, English to machine language zero's and One's feeding the logic gates of the computer transistors. I do not have many friends on my Facebook page, but I love my computer because all my friends live inside it. Visualising the logical pattern of the program in my mind made me awestruck.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Executive

QuantumLink Communications Pvt Ltd [31/01/2017 - 21/11/2018]

City: Mumbai Country: India

- Business or sector: Information and communication
 - I was responsible for handling feature enhancement and bug fixing related to our products which also included understanding the requirements and preparing design documents and Impact Analysis. I used Core Java, JavaScript, Spring, Jquery, Servlet, Freemarker, HTML, Ajax, CSS and MySQL.
 - Developing a Research based web application FieldSense. This project is based on a Salesforce tracking system which is used to track a sales person and worked as an email product which has complete knowledge of network and email protocols to Ensured timely delivery and quality all compliant with the client's quality processes.

QuantumLink Communications Pvt Ltd

Trainee Developer Intern

Vetri Systems [02/03/2016 - 07/04/2016]

City: Salem Country: India

- I worked on a project titled "MEDI SOFT CLOUD BASED MOBILE APPLICATION FOR HEALTH CARE SERVICES". This project was aimed to Automation solution that goes well beyond just field and sales force tracking. The MEDI SOFT mobile app allows your field and sales force to perform a range of routine activities like reaching meeting destinations with real-time navigation assistance.
- I used java micro architecture to create the applications and bootstrap used for the adaptability of the application to all mobile devices.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Computer Science and Engineering

Anna University [05/09/2012 - 25/04/2016]

Address: Anna University, Guindy Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600025 chennai (India)

https://www.annauniv.edu

Mathematics and Computer Science

General Education [02/07/2010 – 22/05/2012]

Address: Department of Government Examinations, Chennai (India)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Docker Container / BIG DATA Knowledge / MACHINE LEARNING / Al and Deep Neural Networks / Computer Vision Basics / Derivatives / Gradient Descent / Natural Languages Processing / Data structures / Web Programming: HTML, CSS, Javascript (front-end), Java (back-end) / programming software engineering software development / Deployment of web servers running IIS, Apache, NGINX / Machine Learning (Andrew Ng course on Coursera) / Algorithm Design / Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning concepts

CREATIVE WORKS

Marvel Image Classifier

[17/07/2020 - Current]

 Transfer learning using Resnet50 Architecture from Fast Al Library (Marvel Heroes Classification) to classify Marvel Heroes based on 12 Classes (Super Heroes)

http://bit.ly/MarvelHeroesClassification

Machine Learning Notes

[07/10/2020 - Current]

• Developing Machine learning Notes for my reference and wrote some difficult topics on layman terms. which were inspired by Andrew NG, Computer Scientist.

http://bit.ly/MLNotesStanford

PROJECTS

Distributed Deep Learning | Horovod | Message Passing Interface(MPI)

[02/05/2018 - 07/06/2018]

- Horovod is a distributed training framework for Keras and TensorFlow. The goal of Horovod is to make distributed Deep Learning fast and easy to use.
- The primary motivation for this project is to make it easy to take a single-GPU TensorFlow program and successfully train it on many GPUs faster.

https://github.com/send2manoo/Distributed-Deep-Learning-With-Horovod-MPI

Image Augmentation Model | Convolutional Neural Network(CNN)

[03/03/2018 - 25/03/2018]

- Automate extraction of Screen shots from Photos.
- I've trained a CNN model to predict Screen Shot files from Album and extract them out of photos directory.

https://github.com/send2manoo/Image-Classification

Object Detection Using Single-Shot Detection(SSD)

[05/11/2018 - Current]

• Worked on Open Source SSD model Using VOC dataset to detect the object in Videos and Photos.

Spark | Distributed cluster | scala | pyspark

[07/09/2017 - 15/09/2017]

- Implement Word Count project using Scala and Build with SBT and run spark jobs across HDFS clusters with the help of YARN.
- Develop spark programmes using pyspark as per the requirement.

https://github.com/send2manoo/Spark-Example

PETAA BYTES ANALYTICS PVT. LTD. (MUMBAI)

Apache Spark Trainee

[17/12/2017 - 05/02/2018]

- Distributed ML computing and setting up servers for production.
- Good working knowledge of spark shell and well known to work on spark using SparkML
- Good knowledge of Spark Core using Scala

Apache Hadoop Trainee

[02/07/2017 - 15/01/2018]

- Worked on Hadoop Cluster with Multi Nodes and with default 128mb capacity.
- Write Mapreduce Jobs, HIVEQL, Pig.
- Import data using Sqoop into Hive and Hbase from existing SQL Server.
- Support code/design analysis, strategy development and project planning.
- Develop multiple MapReduce jobs in Java for data cleaning and preprocessing.
- Involve in creating Hive tables, loading with data and writing Hive queries which will run internally in MapReduce way.
- Operating knowledge of Cloud computing platforms AWS EC2 with S3

CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced Java Programming

[27/05/2016 - 08/08/2016]

C and C++ Programming

[02/07/2014 - 08/10/2014]

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Code Debugging

TECHMEET-2014 [07/03/2014]

First Prize for Code Debugging in TECHMEET-2014 in our college

If you don't succeed at first; call it Alpha version 1.0 clear out most of the major bugs in your life, BE READY FOR BETA VERSION 2.0 AND DEPLOY IT INTO THE FUTURE. - Manohar Palanisamy